nutrisystem.com 2015-10-20

# Nutrisystem.com Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy**

Our Privacy Policy will tell you what information we collect when you visit our site, how we use it and what choices you have about how that information is used. 

At Nutrisystem, we will not share your information, other than to provide our services. Your personal information may be shared with reputable third-party associates of Nutrisystem that work with us to provide products and services to our customer, that help us with marketing campaigns, unless you have expressly asked us not to. We may also disclose your information to third parties if the law requires it or to protect the rights or property of Nutrisystem. We urge you to read our entire Privacy Policy so that you will understand both our commitment to you and your privacy, and how you can participate in that commitment. 

**I.** **_Information You Voluntarily Provide_**

**Personal/Contact Information**

When you place an order on our Site, we collect your name, e-mail address, mailing address, credit card number, and expiration date. The personally identifiable information we collect when you place an order or register for membership on our Site may be used for any of the following purposes: (1) to fulfill your requests for products and services; (2) to notify you of order, delivery, and shipment statuses; (3) to provide you with offers from Nutrisystem; (4) to contact you when necessary; (5) to review Site usage and operations; (6) to address problems with the Site, our business or our products and services; and (7) to protect security or integrity of the Site and our business. We also collect your non-personally identifiable information through our Internet log files, which record data such as user IP addresses, browser types, domain names, and other anonymous statistical data involving the use of our Site. This information may be used for our business purposes. We may link this information to Personally Identifiable Information for these and other purposes, including personalizing your experience on our Website. Information is also collected when you use our Handheld Products, including the software application needed to utilize the Handheld Products on your handheld device (the “Application”). During the installation of the Application and subsequent synchronizations, we collect Non-Personally Identifiable Information concerning your device (such as the specific type of operating system and hardware you have, and the amount of free and total memory) and the Application’s files on your device. 

Our Handheld Products also collect information about your usage of the Application (such as the dates you last synced with the Internet or the dates you last used certain features). When you sync your device with the Website, we store some of this information. 

If you do not want to receive additional promotions from us, please let us know by emailing us at [optout@nutrisystem.com](mailto:optout@nutrisystem.com) or by clicking [here](http://www.nutrisystem.com/jsps_hmr/unsubscribe/enterEmail.jsp). If you opt-out of promotional or newsletter emails from Nutrisystem, we may continue to send you certain transactional communications, such as service announcements and administrative messages relating to Nutrisystem, that are necessary to our relationship with you.

**Health and Age Information**

When you register for membership on our Site, we also collect your basic health profile information when you actively give us such information. The health and age information we collect allows Nutrisystem to evaluate your self-reported health status to determine basic program eligibility. You will be notified at registration if your profile excludes you from participation in the plan. Nutrisystem will not disclose your health and age information (including self-reported height and weight) to third parties. 

**Credit Card and Payment Information**

Nutrisystem does not share any of your payment information with third parties (except to its payment processors).

**Information Provided in Optional Surveys**

Nutrisystem periodically asks members to participate in online surveys or fill out online questionnaires concerning topics such as the effectiveness of the weight loss program, advertising effectiveness and customer satisfaction. All surveys and questionnaires are optional and the information collected will not be associated with any user’s personal information. Information gathered may be shared with third parties in order to improve customer satisfaction and program effectiveness. No personal information of any user will be connected to survey or questionnaire results. 

**Other Information You May Voluntarily Provide**

From time to time, Nutrisystem collects third-party email addresses or other contact information from our users and customers so that Nutrisystem may send information to their friends and family on an as-requested basis. For example, Nutrisystem collects email addresses when a customer provides us with that information so that we may send out Referral Coupons. We also require the same when users utilize certain functions such as “email this to a friend” features. 

**II.** **_Information Provided Automatically_**

**Cookies**

When you use our Site, we gather web traffic information via “cookies”. Cookies are small pieces of digital information stored by your browser on your computer and tracks initial and returning visits, browsing patterns on our site, and products ordered and viewed. Our cookies do not contain personally identifying information, but they enable us to identify you as a repeat visitor and help us personalize your nutrisystem.com experience. Although most browsers are initially set to accept cookies, you may reset your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie or to reject cookies generally. Most browsers offer instructions on how to do so in the "Help" section of the toolbar. You need to have cookies enabled on your computer in order to use our site. If you do not accept cookies to use our Website, you may not be able to use certain resources or features of our Website. 

**How we respond to DO NOT TRACK” signals**

In addition to cookies that we place on your computer, cookies may also be placed on your computer by third parties that we use to display or serve advertisements or to collect non-personally identifiable information in order to provide advertising-related services. For example, in the course of serving advertisements, our third-party ad servers may place or recognize a unique "cookie" on your browser. Neither our third-party ad servers nor their cookies collect personally identifiable information on our Site, and we do not share personally identifiable information with our third party ad servers without your permission. You may "opt-out" of certain tracking on our Site and other websites by various advertising companies through the network advertising initiative. We do not respond to web browser "do not track" signals or other mechanisms that provide you the ability to exercise choice regarding the collection of personal information about your online activities over time and across third-party websites or online services. 

**Flash Cookies**

Certain features of our Website may use local stored objects (or Flash cookies) to collect and store information about your preferences and navigation to, from and on our Website. Flash cookies are not managed by the same browser settings as are used for browser cookies, and they are not placed on your computer. 

**Web Beacons, Pixel Tags, and 3rd Party Cookies**

Nutrisystem, or third parties engaged by us, may use web beacons on some pages of this site. A web beacon (also known as a pixel tag or clear GIF) is a graphic image which is used to better understand the browsing patterns of visitors to the page. 

When the HTML code for the web beacon points to a site to retrieve the pixel image, information can be passed along such as the IP address of the computer that requested the image, the time the web beacon was viewed and for how long, the type of browser that was used, and previously set cookie values. Web beacons DO NOT pass or read personally identifiable information about you. 

Web beacons work in conjunction with cookies set by trusted third parties that are used to assess the effectiveness of particular promotional campaigns or to optimize advertising once a user leaves a website. View your browser’s help section to determine how to configure your browser to reject or manage first part (i.e., Nutrisystem) and/or third-party cookies. Nutrisystem shares aggregated information collected through web beacons to vendors for which the beacon was set to determine the success of marketing campaigns, but does not disclose personally identifying information to these vendors.

Third-party ad servers may track anonymous website usage through web beacons on our Site and other websites. They do this by setting a cookie (or reading a cookie previously placed by them) on users' computers to track the activities of users who view a web page that contains web beacons. Third party ad servers may use information about your visits to this Site and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you. Periodically, upon our request, third party ad servers may report the anonymous data that they collect on our behalf back to us for our internal use and analysis and our treatment of this anonymous data is governed by the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

We may use cookies and web beacons for insight with respect to the usage of the Site, and so that we could continually improve our customer’s experience. At times, we use third parties to analyze usage of our website. However, we do not disclose your personally identifiable information to such third parties. 

**III.** **_What Nutrisystem Does With Your Information_**

**How does Nutrisystem protect customer information?**

Protecting your information from unauthorized disclosure is important to us. We use the industry standard technology to protect the security of your information. We have taken certain physical, electronic, contractual and managerial steps designed to safeguard the information we collect from you. Unfortunately, no data transaction over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. The site operator is not subject to the privacy and data security requirements of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (“GLBA”) or Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (“HIPAA”). 

**Will Nutrisystem disclose the information it collects to outside parties?**

Nutrisystem shares your information (other than payment information) with third-party intermediaries for shipping and billing purposes and with other third-party intermediaries that provide a service for Nutrisystem to help us operate our business and the Site or administer activities on our behalf. These companies may include Cybersource, United Parcel Service, Federal Express, Visa, Mastercard, Discover, and American Express and others.

Nutrisystem may also provide aggregate statistics about our customers, sales, traffic patterns, and related site information to reputable third-party vendors. 

In addition, from time to time, we may make customer e-mail addresses and postal addresses available to other reputable business associates whose products or services might be of value to you. If you do not want us to share your information with other companies or organizations, please let us know by emailing us at [optout@nutrisystem.com](mailto:optout@nutrisystem.com) or by clicking [here](http://www.nutrisystem.com/jsps_hmr/unsubscribe/enterEmail.jsp). If you opt-out of promotional or newsletter emails from Nutrisystem, we may continue to send you certain communications such as service announcements and administrative messages, relating to Nutrisystem that are necessary to our relationship with you.

In addition to what we have described above, Nutrisystem may also disclose your personal information to third parties in certain limited circumstances, as follows (1) as necessary if we believe that there has been a violation of our site Terms and Conditions, of the law, of our rights or of any third party; (2) to respond to judicial process and provide information to law enforcement agencies or in connection with an investigation on matters related to public safety, as permitted by law, or otherwise as required by law; and (3) if you have given permission for us to share your account information with other members of your household. 

Nutrisystem may also sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets, including your personally identifiable information, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets or in the event of bankruptcy. You will have the opportunity to opt out of any such transfer if the new entity's planned use or sharing of your information differs materially from that set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**Mobile Devices/Third-Party Fees**

From time to time, we may make mobile device applications and mobile marketing campaigns available to you and may allow you to register for services that involve messages and/or e-mails being sent to your mobile device. You are responsible for obtaining access to the mobile device services. Such access may involve third-party fees, including mobile carrier, text messaging, or airtime charges. You are solely responsible for those fees, including any and all fees associated with the use of the applications, delivery of the messages, e-mails or other materials to your mobile device. Please consult your mobile service provider's pricing plan prior to purchasing or downloading any application or registering for any such service to determine the charges for sending and receiving text messages from/to your mobile device. You will be given the opportunity to opt-out of receiving text messages or emails to your mobile device at the time you register for the campaign and with each message or email you receive.

Mobile marketing campaigns may involve your sending an e-mail from your mobile device to us or a third-party campaign operator. An e-mail or other response will then be sent to your mobile device. Opting to participate in a campaign is 100% your choice. When you engage in these mobile marketing campaigns, we and the third-party campaign operator may collect your cell phone number, the name of your wireless service provider, images that you send using your cell phone as part of the campaign, and other relevant information. 

**Our Bulletin Boards, Social Media Pages, Chat Rooms & User Blogs**

Our program provides support through bulletin boards, chat rooms (support groups), social media pages and blogs. This format gives our members the opportunity to interact with each other. These areas are moderated to help keep inappropriate messages from being posted. You are offered the opportunity to include your e-mail address with your message, but you are not obligated to do so. Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online (whether it is on message boards, through e-mail, in meeting rooms, on social media pages or in blogs) your information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. We cannot control the actions of any third parties. We reserve the irrevocable, perpetual and worldwide right to copy and post both within the Nutrisystem website, and those of its parent, affiliates, subsidiaries, assigns, agents and licensees and any social media outlets and advertising medium through which we are engaged, any comments, pictures or other information you post on the bulletin boards, social media pages, chat rooms, blogs, or elsewhere on the Nutrisystem community website, without any further notice to you or any remuneration therefore. 

**IV.** **_Your Rights and Your Consent_**

**A Special Note to Parents or Legal Guardians**

Nutrisystem only allows the participation of persons 14 years and older to be on a Nutrisystem program. For legal guardians or parents of children ages 14 – 17 years old, please call 888-995-DIET (3438). For parents interested in helping children younger than14 to lose weight, please consult a physician. This website is not subject to Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”). 

**Notice to California Customers - Your California Privacy Rights**

California’s “Shine the Light” law, Civil Code section 1798.83, requires certain businesses to respond to requests from California customers asking about the businesses’ practices related to disclosing personal information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. Alternately, such businesses may have in place a policy not to disclose personal information of customers to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes if the customer has exercised an option to opt-out of such information-sharing. We have such a policy in place. As discussed above, if you wish to opt-out of our sharing of your information with third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes or to find out more about your opt-out rights, please contact us at the email address described above. 

**Your Consent and Notification of Change**

By using our web site, telephone consultation, or mailing in requests for information you consent to the collection and use of your information by Nutrisystem. We may make non-significant changes to our Privacy Policy that in general will not affect our use of your Personally Identifiable Information at any time by posting the amended terms on this site. All amended terms automatically take effect 30 days after they are posted.

If at some point in the future, there is a material change to our information usage practices that affect your personally identifiable information, we will notify you by e-mail. At the time of this message, you will be able to opt-out of the new information usage by sending a message to the following e-mail: [opt-out@nutrisystem.com](mailto:opt-out@nutrisystem.com) or by clicking [here](http://www.nutrisystem.com/jsps_hmr/unsubscribe/enterEmail.jsp). We may also make non-significant changes to our Privacy Policy that generally will not affect our use of your personally identifiable information. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, you should not use our Website. You should check this posted Privacy Policy for changes. 

**Newsletter**

If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask only for an individual’s e-mail address. Out of respect for our users’ privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications. Click [here](http://www.nutrisystem.com/jsps_hmr/unsubscribe/enterEmail.jsp) to unsubscribe to the nutrisystem.com newsletter. 

**Corrections/Updates**

To make changes to any of your personal information, including name, username, password, shipping address, and telephone number, you can click in the MyAccount section of the Nutrisystem web site or call Nutrisystem at 1-800-585-5483. Household members may not make changes to your account information, or cancel or renew your account without your express permission. If you have not already indicated your permission for household members to access your account at the time you placed your first order, please call 877-338-8446. 

**V.** **_Third-Party Websites_**

Our site may contain links to third-party websites, which may have privacy policies that differ from our own. We are not responsible for the activities and practices that take place on these sites. Accordingly, we recommend that you review the privacy policy posted on any site that you may access through our site. 

**VI.** **_Tell Us What You Think_**

Nutrisystem welcomes your questions and comments about privacy and/or this policy. Please send e-mail to: [feedback@nutrisystem.com](mailto:feedback@nutrisystem.com). 

Nutrisystem, Inc. 600 Office Center Drive Fort Washington, PA 19034 215-706-5300 

Privacy Policy last updated February 18, 2015. 

**Terms and Conditions**

Please also read the Terms and Conditions on the site to understand additional terms and conditions which apply to the use of our Site.
